One man. Countless myths. And in between lies the truth.
Before the End: Searching for Jim Morrison is a
documentary film directed by Jeff Finn.
Documentary film about the iconic 1960s-era poet,
songwriter, and vocalist of the Doors.
Unlike prior Morrison media, Before the End’s focus is on the
humanity behind the hype, including Jim’s formative years.
The documentary features exclusive interviews with his brother, Andy Morrison; cousins Ellen Edwards and David Backer; high school swim coach, Ash Jones; college roommate, Bryan Gates; Doors-era
lovers Judy Huddleston and Anne Moore; Doors booking agent, Todd Schiffman; Doors roadie, Gareth Blyth; and the first appearance by Jim’s Paris-era personal assistant, Robyn Wurtele.
Self (archive footage), played by Jim Morrison.
Self (archive footage), played by Robby Krieger.
Self (archive footage), played by Ray Manzarek.
Self (archive footage), played by John Densmore.
Self, played by Andy Morrison.
Self (archive footage), played by Anne Morrison Chewning.
Superman is a 2025 American superhero film based on
the eponymous character from DC Comics.
Written and directed by James Gunn, it is the first film in the DC
Universe (DCU) and a reboot of the Superman film series.
David Corenswet stars as Kal-El / Clark Kent / Superman, alongside Rachel Brosnahan,
Nicholas Hoult, Edi Gathegi, Anthony Carrigan, Nathan Fillion, and Isabela Merced.
In the film, Superman faces unintended consequences after he intervenes in an
international conflict orchestrated by billionaire Lex Luthor (Hoult).
Superman must win back public support with the help of
his reporter and superhero colleagues.
The film was produced by Gunn and Peter Safran of DC Studios.
Development on a sequel to the DC Extended Universe (DCEU) film Man of Steel (2013)
began by October 2014, with Henry Cavill set to return as Superman.
Plans changed after the troubled production of Justice League (2017), and the
Man of Steel sequel was no longer moving forward by May 2020.
Gunn began work on a new Superman film around August 2022.
In October, he became co-CEO of DC Studios with Safran,
and they began work on a new DC Universe.
Gunn was publicly revealed to be writing the film in December.
The title Superman: Legacy was announced the next month; Gunn was confirmed to direct in
March 2023; and Corenswet and Brosnahan (Lois Lane) were cast that June.
The subtitle was dropped by the end of February 2024,
when filming began in Svalbard, Norway.
Production primarily took place at Trilith Studios in Atlanta,
Georgia, with location filming around Georgia and Ohio.
Filming wrapped in July.
The film's influences include the comic book All-Star Superman
(2005–2008) by Grant Morrison and Frank Quitely.
Superman premiered at the TCL Chinese Theater on July 7,
2025, and was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States on July 11.
It is the first film in the DCU's Chapter One: Gods and Monsters.
The film grossed $617 million worldwide, making it the tenth
highest-grossing film of 2025, and received mostly positive reviews.
Critics found it to be fun, colorful, and earnest, although some felt it was overstuffed,
while the performances of Corenswet, Brosnahan, and Hoult were praised.
A follow-up film, Man of Tomorrow, is scheduled for release in 2027, while a spin-off television series featuring
supporting characters from the film, including Skyler Gisondo's Jimmy Olsen, is in development for HBO Max.